Guide to the John Mitford, Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Collection of 233 letters and envelopes]
1701-1900
OSBORN FC76 1/3
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.44
(3 volumes)
Manuscripts, in multiple hands, of a collection of 233 letters by various notables on numerous subjects, many of them concerning personal affairs. The first volume, for example, contains notes on "Eastward Hoe" and "Old Plays" by S. Pegge and letters by George North on the value of old coins; the second volume contains letters by Voltaire, Horace Walpole, Edmund Burke, Charles Lamb, Robert Peel, and Hannah More, as well as a poem titled "On Faulkners Edition of Swift" by Sir Walter Scott; and the third volume includes a letter by "C. J. Fox" concerning bets "on the Oatlands Stake." Volume I contains items 1-72; vol. II, 73-179; and vol. III 180-233.
Mitford, John, 1781-1859
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn fc76 1/3. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
English literature -- 18th century; English poetry -- 18th century; Letters; Great Britain -- Social life and customs -- 18th century; Great Britain -- Social life and customs -- 19th century; Voltaire, 1694-1778; Burke, Edmund, 1729-1797; Fox, Charles James, 1749-1806; Lamb, Charles, 1775-1834; More, Hannah, 1745-1833; Peel, Robert, 1788-1850; Scott, Walter, 1771-1832
- OSBORN FC76
  - ABERNETHY, JOHN, 1764-1831
    - ALS to [James Arthur Wilson (1795-1882)], [no yr] Mar 6 (Box 2)
      Scope and Contents
      Bedford Row
      1 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      Discusses Abernethy's medical
      opinions about Mr. Wilson's present
      ailment.
      76/II/172
  - ANNE, QUEEN OF GT. BRIT., 1665-1714
    - 3 Documents, signed, 1704,1706 (Box 2)
      Kensington and Windsor
      6 p.; 29 x 20 cm.
      Warrants for payments to regiments
      each with receipt on p.2; signed also
      by Henry St. John, 1st viscount
      Bolingbroke (1678-1751).
      Women Writers
      76/II/76-78
  - ARBUTHNOT, GEORGE, 1802-1865
    - ALS to Thomas Collins, 1843 Dec 8 (Box 1)
      Whitehall
      3 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
      Cannot grant access desired to a
      portrait; mentions Sir Robert Peel,
      2nd bart. (1788-1850).
      76/I/72
  - ASHBURTON, WILLIAM BINGHAM BARING, 2ND BARON, 1799-1864
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1841 Aug 10 (Box 3)
      Alresford
      1 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
      Answering a letter presumably asking
      Ashburton to see his pictures which
      are, at the date of the letter,
      "covered up".
      76/III/232
  - BALFOUR, JOHN, 1745-1795
    - ALS to James Dodsley (1724-1797), 1766 Mar 18 (Box 1)
      Edinburgh
      1 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      Advises offering 60 Gns. for a new
      edition; mentions John Gregory
      (1724-1773).
      76/I/17
  - BARTON, BERNARD, 1784-1849
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1826 Jul 12 (Box 2)
      Woodbridge
      1 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      Quotes from a letter to him
      from Charles Lamb (1775-1834).
      76/II/135
  - BERKENHOUT, JOHN, 1730?-1791
    - ALS to Robert Dodsley (1703-1764), 1754 Feb 26 (Box 1)
      Greenwich
      About the translation of the
      "Messiah" of Friedrich Gottlieb
      Klopstock (1724-1803).
      76/I/27
  - BERKENHOUT, JOHN, 1730?-1791
    - ALS to James Dodsley (1724-1797), 1776 Sep 22 (Box 1)
      Richmond
      2 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      Offers first vol. for £300.
      76/I/28
  - BLOMFIELD, CHARLES JAMES, BP. OF LONDON, 1786-1857
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), [1819] (Box 2)
      [1819 or later] Nov 7
      Chesterford
      About classical texts lent to him by
      Mitford and which he would keep no
      longer.
      76/II/143
  - BOLINGBROKE, HENRY ST. JOHN, 1ST VISCOUNT, 1678-1751
    - LS to Worsley, 1714 Apr 20 (Box 2)
      4 p.; 30 x 18 cm.
      Discusses protocol and treaty
      concerning a visit to the Portuguese
      court; includes a discussion of
      wines.
      76/II/79
  - BOWLES, WILLIAM LISLE, 1762-1850
    - ALS to John Gough Nichols (1806-1873), 1836 Mar 10 (Box 1)
      Salisbury
      4 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      76/I/44
  - BOWLES, WILLIAM LISLE, 1762-1850
    - ALS to [John Gough Nichols (1806-1873)], 1834 Jun 3 (Box 1)
      Bremhill
      4 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
      76/I/45
  - BOWLES, WILLIAM LISLE, 1762-1850
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1835 Dec 12 (Box 1)
      3 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      76/I/46
  - BOWLES, WILLIAM LISLE, 1762-1850
    - ALS to William Pickering (1796-1854), 1835 Dec 17 (Box 1)
      4 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      76/I/47
  - BOWLES, MADGDALENE (WAKE) [MRS. WILLIAM LISLE BOWLES]
    - ALS to John Gough Nichols (1806-1873), 1835 Dec 20 (Box 1)
      3 p.; 19 x 11 cm.
      Writes on behalf of her husband in
      order to defer his poems until the
      Spring.
      76/I/48
  - BOWLES, WILLIAM LISLE, 1762-1850
    - 13 ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1836-39 (Box 1)
      Salisbury and Bremhill
      28 p.; various sizes
      76/I/49-55, 57-62
  - BOWLES, WILLIAM LISLE, 1762-1850
    - ALS to William Pickering (1796-1854), 1837 Jul 4 (Box 1)
      76/I/56
  - BRITTON, JOHN, 1771-1857
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1837 Jun 23 (Box 1)
      n.p.
      1 p.; 25 x 19 cm.
      Concerns a letter of recommendation
      by William Beckford (1760-1844) for
      Mitford's use while in Bath.
      76/I/41
  - BRITTON, JOHN, 1771-1857
    - ALS to John Bowyer Nichols (1779-1863), 1836 Sep 3 (Box 3)
      [London]
      Quotes for Mitford (Nichols's
      "friend") a letter from William
      Beckford. Written on a blank page of
      prospectus for Britton's book on
      Cassiobury-Park.
      76/III/193
  - BROUGHAM AND VAUX, HENRY PETER BROUGHAM, 1ST BARON, 1778-1868
    - 3 ALS to unnamed recipients, 1821-33 and n.d. (Box 2)
      various places
      5 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Short notes mainly concerning
      unanswered correspondence and his
      social obligations.
      76/II/174-176
  - BRUNS, PAUL JAKOB, 1743-1814
    - ALS to James Chelsum (1740-1801), 1790 Mar 29 (Box 1)
      Helmstadt
      Introducing the recipient to the
      Professor Eberhard August Wilhelm
      von Zimmerman (d. 1815).
      76/I/31
  - BUCHAN, DAVID STEUART ERSKINE, 11TH EARL OF, 1742-1829
    - ALS to Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821), 1794 Jul 15 (Box 1)
      Dryburgh Abbey
      3 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      Discusses his intentions to visit
      America and to study its schools.
      76/I/29
  - BUNBURY, SIR HENRY EDWARD, 7TH BART., 1778-1860
    - Memorandum: MS copy (Box 3)
      3 p.; 18 x 188 cm.
      On the paintings of Sir Joshua
      Reynolds (1723-1792) with a list of
      the 9 at Barton Hall.
      76/III/181
  - BURGESS, GEORGE, 1786-1864
    - 4 ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1855 [no date] (Box 3)
      London
      16 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      On his classical studies.
      76/III/216-219
  - BURGESS, THOMAS, FL. 1766-1786
    - ALS to James Baynes (1766-1837), n.d. (Box 2)
      [Waltham]
      1 p.; 14 x 16 cm.
      Invitation to Baynes.
      76/II/88
  - BURKE, EDMUND, 1729-1797
    - LS to Edmond Malone (1741-1812), 1797 Apr 16 (Box 2)
      Bath
      Mentions an enclosure of signed
      "Letters to the Execution of Prince
      Potemkin".
      76/II/132
  - CANNING, GEORGE, 1770-1827
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1811 Nov 16 (Box 2)
      Girall[?]
      3 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
      Payment of a pension.
      76/II/159
  - CANNING, GEORGE, 1770-1827
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1817 Aug 22 (Box 2)
      Gloucester Lodge
      1 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
      Thanks the recipient for sending a
      "packet".
      76/II/160
  - CANOVA, ANTONIO, 1757-1822
    - Letter (copy) to William Paulet Carey (1759-1839), 1822 Apr 12 (Box 2)
      Rome
      A letter of thanks.
      76/II/73
  - CARLYLE, THOMAS, 1795-1881
    - ALS to Edward Fitzgerald (1809-1883), 1855 Oct 20 (Box 3)
      Chelsea
      4 p.; 20 x 16 cm.
      His opinion of Johann Christoph
      Friedrich von Schiller (1759-1805).
      76/III/220
  - CARY, HENRY FRANCIS, 1772-1844
    - 2 ALS to [John Mitford (1781-1859)], 1840 Dec 5-8 (Box 2)
      Park Street, Westminster
      2 p., 1 p.; 23 x 19 cm.. 19 x 12 cm.
      Concerning his editing "the British
      Poets", in particular Edward Young
      (1683-1765); 76/II/170 concerns the
      text of the dedication of "Revenge."
      76/II/169-170
  - CLARKE, EDWARD DANIEL, 1769-1822
    - ALS to Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821), 1796 May 8 (Box 1)
      Uckfield
      8 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      Criticisms of James Boswell
      (1740-1795).
      76/I/33
  - CLARKE, EDWARD DANIEL, 1769-1822
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1812 Nov 16 (Box 1)
      Trumpington
      Discusses a letter by Mitford which
      he forwarded to George Walpole
      (1758-1835).
      76/I/34
  - COOKESLEY, WILLIAM GIFFORD, 1802-1880
    - ALS to [George?] Williams (1814-1878), [1852] (Box 3)
      [1852 or later] Jul 27
      Eton College
      4 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      On matters of Eton College.
      76/III/215
  - COPLESTON, EDWARD, BP. OF LLANDAFF, 1776-1849
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1811 Mar 17 (Box 2)
      Oriel College
      Comments on a poem by Thomas Gray
      (1716-1771).
      76/II/149
  - COPLESTON, EDWARD, BP. OF LLANDAFF, 1776-1849
    - Memorandum: autograph MS (Box 2)
      Translation into Greek of the poem
      "Three children sliding on the ice".
      76/II/148
  - CRABBE, GEORGE, 1754-1832
    - AL (signature cut out) to George Crabbe, Jr. (1785-1857), 1825 Dec 11 (Box 2)
      Beccles
      Discussing his son's study of
      religion, history, etc.
      76/II/155
  - DAMPIER, THOMAS, BP. OF ELY, 1748-1812
    - ALS to [Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821)], 1802 Sep 13 (Box 3)
      Harley Street
      Explains his refusal to ordain a
      candidate whom Knox had obviously
      recommended.
      76/III/196
  - DAMPIER, THOMAS, BP. OF ELY, 1748-1812
    - ALS to [Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821)], 1806 Dec 8 (Box 3)
      Bromley House
      Ordination of Thomas Knox (d. 1843).
      76/III/197
  - D'ISRAELI, ISAAC, 1766-1848
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1837 Jun 8 (Box 1)
      Athenaeum
      76/I/40
  - D'ISRAELI, ISAAC, 1766-1848
    - ALS to Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821), 1786 Apr 10 (Box 2)
      3 p.; 25 x 19 cm.
      Seeks discipleship.
      76/II/116
  - D'ISRAELI, ISAAC, 1766-1848
    - ALS to Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821), 1786 Apr 20 (Box 2)
      Rebuffed, but grateful for advice.
      76/II/117
  - DODSLEY, JAMES, 1724-1797
    - AL (draft) to John Balfour (ca.1745-1795), 1766 Mar 22 (Box 1)
      3 p.; 19 x 15 cm.
      Concerning a manuscript by John
      Gregory (1724-1773).
      76/I/18
  - DODSLEY, JAMES, 1724-1797
    - AL (draft) to T. Hooke, 1766 Mar 22 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 19 x 15 cm.
      Concerns future publications and
      other matters of business.
      76/I/19 - written on p.4 of 76/I/18.
  - DRAKENBORCH, ARNOLD, 1684-1748
    - ALS (in Dutch) to anonymous bride and bridegroom, 1747 Jan 19 (Box 1)
      Utrecht
      2 p.; 20 x 16 cm.
      Accompanied by a translation.
      76/I/5
  - DYCE, ALEXANDER. 1798-1869
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), n.d. (Box 3)
      9 Grays Inn Square
      2 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Literary matters.
      76/III/222
  - FACCIOLATI, GIACOMO, 1682-1769
    - ALS (in Italian) to an unnamed recipient, 1724 Sep 28 (Box 1)
      Padua
      2 p.; 24 x 17 cm.
      76/I/6
  - FIELDING, HENRY, 1707-1754
    - Memorandum: autograph MS (Box 2)
      1 p.; 28 x 19 cm.
      Judicial procedure with certification
      of authenticity by his grandson,
      William Henry Fielding, appended
      (1832).
      76/II/80
  - FORSTER, JOHN, 1812-1876
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1835 Dec 10 (Box 3)
      58 Lincoln's Inn Fields
      4 p.; 11 x 19 cm.
      Discusses location of works by Sir
      Joshua Reynolds (1723-1792).
      76/III/225
  - FOX, CHARLES JAMES, 1749-1806
    - ALS to Dennis O'Bryen (1755-1832), [1802 May 10] (Box 2)
      St. Anne's Hill
      Discusses his plans to "try" for a
      seat in Parliament.
      76/II/144
  - FOX, CHARLES JAMES, 1749-1806
    - "To a Handsome Woman by the Honble. Ca. Fox": MS copy (Box 2)
      Copy of a fable in the form of a
      letter to a "Handsome Woman".
      Water-marked 1807.
      76/II/145
  - FOX, CHARLES JAMES, 1749-1806
    - Signature on an envelope, 1806 Mar 11 (Box 2)
      1 p.; 6 x 11 cm.
      76/II/92
  - FOX, CHARLES JAMES, 1749-1806
    - ALS to William Davis, [1791 Jun 24] (Box 3)
      Concerning a list of bets he sends
      to the recipient.
      76/III/190
  - FOX, CHARLES JAMES, 1749-1806
    - ALS to Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821), 1806 Mar, 11 (Box 3)
      Thanks for congratulations.
      76/III/191
  - GAINSBOROUGH, THOMAS, 1727-1788
    - 2 letters (copies) to an unnamed recipient, 1757 (Box 3)
      1757 Feb 25, Mar 13
      Ipswich
      2 p.; 21 x 17 cm.
      Portraits to be painted in Colchester
      defense of his technique.
      76/III/180
  - GILPIN, WILLIAM, 1724-1804
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1776 Aug 15 (Box 2)
      Cheam
      2 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      Asks after the recipient and relates
      an anecdote about a Mr. Mason's
      comments concerning some poetry the
      recipient had sent the author.
      76/II/106
  - GILPIN, WILLIAM, 1724-1804
    - 2 ALS to James Chelsum (1740-1801), 1789-90 (Box 2)
      Vicar's Hill
      6 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      76/II/107-108
  - GIRDLESTONE, SAMUEL, 1767-
    - ALS to Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821), 1809 Jan 14 (Box 3)
      Lincoln's Inn
      2 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
      Sending a son to Tunbridge school.
      76/III/211
  - GREY, SIR CHARLES EDWARD, 1785-1865
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1814 Dec 28 (Box 1)
      Paris
      4 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      Notes on a tour in France.
      76/I/37
  - HEY, RICHARD, 1745-1835
    - ALS to Vernor & Hood, publishers, 1795 Mar 9 (Box 2)
      York
      3 p.; 20 x 16 cm.
      On the sales of his works.
      76/II/120
  - HOADLY, JOHN, 1711-1776
    - 2 ALS to John Duncombe, 1729-1786, 1773 (Box 2)
      1773 Jan 4, Apr 30
      St. Cross
      10 p.; 20 x 16 cm.
      On publication of works by John
      Hughes (1677-1720).
      76/II/104-105
  - HOARE, SIR RICHARD COLT, 2ND BART., 1758-1838
    - ALS to [John Mitford (1781-1859)], n.d. (Box 2)
      Stourhead
      1 p.; 18 x 20 cm.
      Discusses briefly images of
      landscape.
      76/II/137
  - HOLLAND, HENRY RICHARD VASSALL FOX, 3RD BARON, 1773-1840
    - ALS to William Henry Cavendish Bentinck, 3rd duke of Portland (1738-1809), 1798 Sep 25 (Box 2)
      Holland House
      2 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      Against forfeiture of the property
      of Lord Edward Fitzgerald
      (1763-1798).
  - HOME, JOHN, 1722-1808
    - AL to Thomas Cadell, [ca. 1780] (Box 2)
      [Edinburgh]
      2 p.; 20 x 15 cm.
      Asks for help in finding a pamphlet.
      76/II/87
  - HORSELY, SAMUEL, BP. OF ST. ASAPH, 1733-1806
    - ALS to Mr. Wraughton, 1777 Jul 2 (Box 2)
      Aldbury
      Books from Mr. Wraughton's shop to
      be forwarded.
      76/II/110
  - HORSELY, SAMUEL, BP. OF ST. ASAPH, 1733-1806
    - ALS to [Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821)], 1800 Apr 17 (Box 3)
      Thanks for his essay.
      76/III/195
  - HOUBIGANT, CHARLES FRANCOIS, 1686-1783
    - ALS to Mr. Chelmin, 1779 Jun 20 (Box 2)
      1 p.; 19 x 11 cm.
      Awaits 2nd. volume of verses edited
      from the hebrew MSS by Benjamin
      Kennicott (1718-1783).
      76/II/111
  - HURDIS, JAMES, 1763-1801
    - ALS to Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821), 1786 Nov 4 (Box 3)
      Seaford
      Thanks Knox for his concern about
      his son's health.
      76/III/201
  - JONES, SIR WILLIAM, 1746-1794
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1781 Jul 14 (Box 2)
      University College, Oxford
      Prescribed format for his Arabian
      Poems.
      76/II/112
  - KNIGHT, SAMUEL, 1675-1746
    - 2 ALS to Robert Moss, 1666-1729, 1725-26 (Box 1)
      1725 Nov 25, 1726 Jun 16
      Ely
      6 p.; 21 x 16 cm.
      Concerns affairs of parish.
      76/I/7,8
  - KNOX, VICESIMUS, 1752-1821
    - "On Arabin's Speech in Jones versus Smith at the Sheriffs Court - London": autograph MS verse, [1803 or later] (Box 3)
      4 p.; 33 x 20 cm.
      76/III/214
  - KNOX, VICESIMUS, JR.
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1848 Feb 9 (Box 2)
      Stratford Place
      Sends to Mitford two letters from
      Isaac D'Israeli (1766-1848) to his
      father, Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821).
      76/II/115
  - LAMB, CHARLES, 1775-1834
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1824 Dec 16 (Box 2)
      India House
      1p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      About patterns for vases, being made
      in Canton, that Mitford has ordered.
      76/II/136
  - LANSDOWNE, HENRY PETTY-FITZMAURICE, 3RD MARQUIS OF, 1780-1863
    - ALS to William Lisle Bowles (1762-1850), n.d. (Box 2)
      Bowood
      Concerns the statues in his garden
      which a friend has asked to see.
      76/II/173
  - LEFANU, ALICIA (SHERIDAN), 1753-1817
    - ALS to [Elizabeth Ann (Linley) Sheridan (1754-1792)], [1788?] May 20 (Box 3)
      Making an appointment.
      76/III/188
  - L'ESTRANGE, SIR ROGER, 1616-1704
    - Document, signed, 1678 Jun 15 (Box 2)
      1 p.; 29 x 19 cm.
      Relinquishing his rights in licensing
      papers, blanks and forms to William
      Paston appointed official supplier.
      76/II/74
  - LIGHTFOOT, JOHN, 1602-1675
    - ALS to Samuel Clarke (1625-1669), 1661 Jul 3 (Box 2)
      Cambridge
      1 p.; 20 x 15 cm.
      Reactions to a book sent to him by
      Clarke.
      76/II/75
  - LORT, MICHAEL, 1725-1790
    - 2 ALS to Mr. Pritchard, 1761 (Box 1)
      1761 Sep 10, 1761 Oct 12
      7 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      On "A Discourse of Freethinking" by
      Anthony Collins (1672-1729); contains
      a biographical note on Pritchard on
      p. 4 of the first letter initialled
      by Lort.
      76/I/15,16
  - MACKINTOSH, SIR JAMES, 1765-1832
    - 2 ALS and 2 AL to Samuel Rogers (1763-1855) (Box 2)
      4 p.; various sizes
      Social engagement notes.
      76/II/165-168
  - MACKINTOSH, SIR JAMES, 1765-1832
    - "A Critique on Mr Fox's Historical Work by Sir James Mackintosh": [autograph] MS, n.d. (Box 3)
      16 p. (incomplete); 23 x 19 cm.
      Critique of work written by Charles
      James Fox (1749-1806).
      76/III/192
  - MACLAINE, ARCHIBALD, 1722-1804
    - ALS to James Chelsum (1740-1801), 1778 Oct 26 (Box 1)
      The Hague
      Protests his friendship and
      obligation.
      76/I/23
  - MADOX, THOMAS, 1666-1727
    - ALS to William Nicolson (bp. of Derry, 1655-1727), 1706 Jun 8 (Box 1)
      3 p.; 19 x 16 cm.
      On the keeping of the records in the
      Tower; mentions William Petty
      (1636-1707).
      76/I/2
  - MAGEE, WILLIAM, ABP. OF DUBLIN, 1766-1831
    - ALS to an unnamed bookseller, 1806 Jun 30 (Box 2)
      Dublin
      Thanks for the books sent and orders
      others urgently.
      76/II/147
  - MAITLAND, WILLIAM, 1693?-1757
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1740 Jul 1 (Box 1)
      Poultry
      To a correspondent claiming to have
      helped him.
      76/I/3
  - MAITTAIRE, MICHAEL, 1668-1747
    - Memorandum: autograph MS (Box 2)
      1 p.; 8 x 24 cm.
      Denies editorship of certain volumes.
      76/II/81
  - MALONE, EDMOND, 1741-1812
    - ALS to [James Bindley? (1737-1818)], 1797 Oct 5 (Box 2)
      Queen Anne St. E.
      Discusses his current projects.
      76/II/133
  - MANGEY, THOMAS, 1688-1755
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1746 Aug 21 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 13 x 12 cm.
      Returns "the Terence, choosing rather
      to have Dr. Bentley's Edition".
      76/I/4
  - MANGEY, THOMAS, 1688-1755
    - ALS to Dr. Waller, 1720 Mar 4 (Box 2)
      A new treatment for the smallpox.
      76/II/83
  - MARKLAND, JEREMIAH, 1693-1776
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1772 Aug 23 (Box 2)
      n.p. [Dorking?]
      1 p.; 21 x 17 cm.
      76/II/98
  - MARKLAND, JEREMIAH, 1693-1776
    - ALS to [William] Clarke (1696-1771), 1751 Sep 2 (Box 2)
      Uckfield 1 p.; 24 x 19 cm. Discusses plans for a voyage to Findon and Brighthelmston as well as the price of "Mr. James's House". 76/II/97
  - MARLBOROUGH, SARAH (JENNINGS) CHURCHILL, DUCHESS OF, 1660-1774
    - Document, signed, [no yr] Jul 15 (Box 2)
      1 p.; 9 x 15 cm.
      Signature and a notation for a bill
      for coals.
      76/II/84
  - MARTIN, THOMAS, 1697-1771
    - ALS to Mr. Hubbard, 1766 Dec 31 (Box 2)
      Palgrave
      2 p.; 19 x 16 cm.
      On the printing of the "History of
      Leicester".
      76/II/103
  - MASON, WILLIAM, 1724-1797
    - AL to Mr. Leigh, n.d. (Box 2)
      1 p.; 20 x 16 cm.
      Sends to Mr. Leigh documents for
      the inspection of Samuel Pegge
      (1704-1796).
      76/II/96
  - MASON, WILLIAM, 1724-1797
    - ALS to [Henry] Bryant (1721-1799), 1747 Nov 13 (Box 2)
      St. John's College, Cambridge
      News of college friends.
      76/II/95
  - MATHIAS, THOMAS JAMES, 1754-1835
    - ALS (in Latin) to Michael Lort (1725-1790), n.d. (Box 1)
      76/I/14
  - MELBOURNE, WILLIAM LAMB, 2ND VISCOUNT, 1779-1848
    - ALS to Thomas Young, [ca. 1832] (Box 1)
      1 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Concerning an anonymous man's
      appointment to the police.
      76/I/68
  - [MEMORANDUM ON JAMES BYERS (1733-1817)
    - Anonymous Manuscript, 1843 Jan 23 (Box 1)
      2 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
      76/I/69
  - MIDDLETON, CONYERS, 1683-1750
    - ALS to [Zachary] Grey (1688-1766), 1739 Mar 28 (Box 2)
      [Cambridge]
      1 p.; 17 x 24 cm.
      Sends receipts to be distributed.
      76/II/85
  - MIDDLETON, CONYERS, 1683-1750
    - ALS to [Zachary] Grey (1688-1766), 1744 Apr 24 (Box 2)
      Has collected more subscriptions for
      Grey.
      76/II/86
  - MILLES, JEREMIAH, 1714-1784
    - ALS to [John Nichols (1745-1826)], 1779 Feb 11 (Box 1)
      Concerns the "anonymous memoirs" of
      William Bowyer (1699-1777).
      76/I/24
  - MITFORD, JOHN, 1781-1859
    - AL to Mr. and Mrs. Reynolds, [no yr] Jun 12 (Box 2)
      Clarges Street
      Invitation to dinner.
      76/II/140
  - MITFORD, JOHN, 1781-1859
    - 7 ALS to Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821), 1791-1795 (Box 3)
      10 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      His boys, John and Robert, at
      Tunbridge school.
      76/III/203-206, 208-210
  - MITFORD, JOHN, D. 1806
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1793 May 8 (Box 3)
      Writes to his son, at Tunbridge
      school, to ask him to arrange for
      accommodations for himself and
      Mitford's sisters during their
      upcoming visit.
      76/III/207
  - MITFORD, SARAH
    - Signature, 1770 Mar (Box 2)
      1 p.; 11 x 14 cm.
      Annotated by John Mitford (1781-1859)
      as his only specimen of his mother's
      writing.
      76/II/141
  - MITFORD, WILLIAM, 1744-1827
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), [no yr] Mar 21 (Box 2)
      Cork Street
      Concerns the sale of Madeira in pipes
      to be held at India House.
      76/II/142
  - MITFORD, WILLIAM, 1744-1827
    - Memoranda: autograph MS, 1817 Apr 14 (Box 2)
      Topographical directions for views
      in the New Forest; addressed to John
      Mitford (1781-1859).
      76/II/138-139
  - MONTAGU, EDWARD WORTLEY, 1713-1776
    - ALS (incomplete) to [Sir William Watson? (1715-1787], 1773 Mar 28 (Box 1)
      Rosette, Egypt
      3 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Concerns his trip in Egypt.
      76/I/32
  - MORANT, PHILIP, 1700-1770
    - ALS to Richard Gough (1735-1809), 1769 Sep 5 (Box 1)
      [Colchester]
      Offers corrections for Gough's work.
      76/I/20
  - MORE, HANNAH, 1745-1833
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1827 Apr 17 (Box 2)
      Barley Wood
      2 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
      Concerns a threatened lawsuit.
      76/II/157